<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Aguirre</title>
    <link>https://daguirreag.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daniel Aguirre</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 18:51:39 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daguirreag.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my own Home lab: Software</title>
      <link>https://daguirreag.github.io/posts/setting-up-my-own-home-lab-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 18:51:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daguirreag.github.io/posts/setting-up-my-own-home-lab-software/</guid>
      <description>With the homelab hardware set up, it is time to start preparing the machines so they can work together. As I intend to use my homelab as a safe and easy to use &amp;ldquo;IT playground&amp;rdquo;, I have decided that the following elements would need to be setup:
Static IP address on each machine. This facilitates troubleshooting as well as easing the communication between the machines. Remote control software and SSH. This facilitates troubleshooting my &amp;ldquo;remote&amp;rdquo; machines without having to hook a keyboard+mouse+monitor to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my own Home lab: Hardware/Networking</title>
      <link>https://daguirreag.github.io/posts/setting-up-my-own-home-lab-hardware-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 21:59:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daguirreag.github.io/posts/setting-up-my-own-home-lab-hardware-networking/</guid>
      <description>As a data engineer, it is quite obvious that I like tinkering with technology, specially with software related stuff. Because of this, some time ago I decided to setup my own simple homelab where I could experiment and run scripts around without worrying about setting up cloud services.
As such, I have decided to share how I set up my homelab, so others can use it as an inspiration or just have a look at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://daguirreag.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daguirreag.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://daguirreag.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daguirreag.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Data engineering 💽 Financial news collectors - Financial news collector and aggregator service. IP-to-Geolocation - Proof of concept of a IP-to-Geolocation web application. It returns the geographic location of a given IP address. Software engineering 🧑‍💻 STL to gif - A Python script to create a gif file from a STL file. URL-shortener - Proof of concept of a URL shortener application. Feedback-functionality - A simple implementation to add the functionality to collect user provided feedback via website forms to your websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
